美国海军于1969年3月3日
为顶尖飞行员成立菁英学校
目的是教导失传的空战技巧
并确保这少数的男女学员在毕业后
成为世上最顶尖的战机飞行员
成绩斐然
海军称之为战斗机武器学校
飞行员则称之为
扞卫战士：独行侠
（加州莫哈维沙漠）
（9马赫）
（彼得“独行侠”米契尔上校 试飞员）
（管制区）
嘿
Hey.
怎么回事？
What is it?
怎么了？
What?
我们奉命禁飞，计划被取消
We've been ordered to stand down.
They're scrapping the program.
他们说我们没达标
They say we fell short.
合约门槛是10马赫
The contract threshold is Mach 10.
那是两个月后的门槛，今天是9马赫
Mach 10 is supposed to be in two months.
Today's test point is Mach 9.
这不够好
Well that's not good enough.
谁说的？
Says who?
坎恩少将
Admiral Cain.
无人机骑兵
The Drone Ranger.
他要为无人机计划挪用我们的预算
He wants our budget for his unmanned program.
现在正赶来亲自终止今天的试飞
He's on his way to kill the test and shut us down personally.
他还没到
Well he isn't here yet.
他们要10马赫
They want Mach 10
就给他们10马赫
let's give 'em Mach 10.
（独行侠）
记住，合约门槛是10马赫
Now remember the contract threshold is Mach 10.
不是10.1或10.2，是10马赫
Not 10.1. Not 10.2. Mach 10.
这样计划就可以继续下去
That should keep the program alive.
我不喜欢你这个表情
I don't like that look Mav.
我只有这一号表情
It's the only one I got.
这是暗星，收到吗？
Control this is Darkstar. How do you read?
这是控制中心，收到了，你呢？
Darkstar Control. Loud and clear. How me?
收到，完成飞前检查
Loud and clear. Takeoff precheck's complete.
启动辅助动力
Ready for APU start.
启动左引擎
Ready left engine start.
启动右引擎
Ready right engine start.
滑行准备
Thumbs for taxi.
开始滑行
We are ready for taxi.
塔台，这是暗星，我正准备滑行
Tower this is Darkstar. We are taxiing with information Alpha.
暗星，可以滑行
Darkstar you are clear to taxi.
21跑道，风向210，风速10节
Runway 21. Winds 210 10.
-油温正常
-同意
-Fuel temps are looking good.
-Control concurs.
电池量95%，舱压正常
Battery's holding at 95%. Cabin pressure looks good.
同意
Control concurs.
这是暗星，准备起飞
Tower this is Darkstar. We're ready for takeoff.
要求爬升至600尺以上
Requesting an unrestricted climb to 600 and above.
暗星，尽管起飞吧
Darkstar the runway and skies are yours.
切斯特坎恩少将
Rear Admiral Chester Cain.
独行侠，坎恩到了大门
Maverick Cain just pulled up to the gate.
喊卡还来得及
It's not too late to stop buddy.
你知道这么做的后果
You know what happens to you if you go through with this.
我知道不这么做大家都会失业
I know what happens to everyone else if I don't.
暗星准备起飞
Darkstar is ready for takeoff.
大伙儿
Everyone
准备起飞，先从引擎开始
go for takeoff starting with engine.
-引擎，行
-热源影像系统，行
-Engine go.
-Thermals go.
-燃油，行
-电力系统，行
-Fuel go.
-Electric go.
控制面，行
Control surfaces go.
暗星，你可以起飞
Darkstar Control. You're cleared for takeoff.
好吧，宝贝
All right sweetheart
最后一次飞行
one last ride.
爬升至600尺后，加速到3.5马赫
Darkstar you are cleared above 600. Increase to Mach 3.5.
Cleared above 600. Increase to Mach 3.5.
少将
Admiral.
-来得刚好
-我提早了，你也是
-Just in time sir.
-I'm early. So are you.
可以解释吗？
You care to explain?
切换到超音速燃烧冲压引擎
Transitioning to scramjet.
坎恩少将要求…
Mav Admiral Cain is asking--
-命令
-命令你立刻降落
-Ordering.
-Ordering that we bring her down.
爬…升…
目前已经爬升至…
爬升至六…
...within six...
通讯不稳定，长官
This is where we've had trouble with comms sir.
因为地球曲面差，这叫地球隆起
It's the Earth's curvature. It's called "Earth Bulge."
有人替你倒咖啡吗？
Did anyone offer you a coffee?
Okay.
达到7马赫，逼近8马赫
He's at Mach 7 pushing 8.
-飞行数据？
-数据没问题
-Flight data?
-Receiving. Data is good.
油温升高，引擎仍然稳定
Temperature's climbing. Response is still stable.
感觉很好
We're feeling good.
8.8马赫
Mach 8.8.
8.9
9马赫
Mach 9.
他是世上最快的人
He's the fastest man alive.
呆头鹅，看到了吗？
Talk to me Goose.
9.1马赫
Mach 9.1.
9.2
9.3马赫
Mach 9.3.
9.4
接近超高音速
Approaching high hypersonic.
风挡过热警示
Windshield hot caution.
机身温度升高
Surface temp rising.
快啊，宝贝，再快一点
Come on sweetheart just a little more.
只差一点了
Just a little.
快啊！
Come on!
10马赫！
Mach 10!
把它放回你的国防预算中！
Put that in your Pentagon budget!
长官
Sir.
噢，不要
Don't do it. Don't do it.
只要…
Just...
再加一把劲
a little push.
惨了
Holy shit.
作为飞官你很带种
You got some balls stick jockey.
我不得不承认
I'll give you that.
噢，惨了
Oh shit.
独行侠
Maverick.
独行侠！
Maverick!
谢谢
Thank you.
我在哪里？
Where am I?
地球
Earth.
独行侠
Maverick.
三十多年的军旅生涯
Thirty-plus years of service.
战功勋章
Combat medals.
奖项无数
Citations.
四十年来唯一击落三架敌机的人
Only man to shoot down three enemy planes
in the last 40 years.
杰出服役勋章
"Distinguished."
杰出服役勋章、杰出服役勋章
"Distinguished." "Distinguished."
但你却升不了官，也不肯退役
Yet you can't get a promotion you won't retire
尽管多次出生入死，却又死不了
and despite your best efforts you refuse to die.
早就该成为二星少将，或是参议员
You should be at least a two-star admiral
by now if not a senator.
但你仍留在这里
Yet here you are:
上校
Captain.
为什么？
Why is that?
人生就是如此难解，长官
It's one of life's mysteries sir.
这不是笑话，我在问你问题
This isn't a joke. I asked you a question.
这是我的归属，长官
I'm where I belong sir.
海军不这么认为
Well the navy doesn't see it that way.
不再是如此
Not anymore.
你试飞的战机
These planes you've been testing
上校
Captain
迟早有一天不再需要飞行员
one day sooner than later they won't need pilots at all.
需要吃喝拉撒睡的飞行员
Pilots that need to sleep eat take a piss.
违反命令的飞行员
Pilots that disobey orders.
你只是为其他人争取一些时间
All you did was buy some time for those men out there.
未来近在咫尺
The future is coming
而你不会参与其中
and you're not in it.
把他带出基地
Escort this man off the base.
到他的寝室，看着他打包
Take him to his quarters.
Wait with him while he packs his gear.
一小时内出发前往北岛航空站
I want him on the road to North Island within the hour.
北岛航空站？
North Island sir?
有一通电话来得时机刚刚好
Call came in with impeccable timing
就在我准备罚你永远禁飞之前
right as I was driving here to
ground your ass once and for all.
我很不想说，但是…
It galls me to say it but...
只有老天爷和你的守护天使知道原因
for reasons known only to
the Almighty and your guardian angel...
你又被召回扞卫战士学校
you've been called back to TOPGUN.
-长官？
-解散，上校
-Sir?
-You are dismissed Captain.
结局是无可避免的，独行侠
The end is inevitable Maverick.
你这种飞官总有一天会被淘汰
Your kind is headed for extinction.
也许吧，长官
Maybe so sir.
但不是今天
But not today.
（加州圣地牙哥，美国战机城）
（太平洋舰队 美军海军航空队）
（汤姆“冰人”卡赞斯基 美国太平洋舰队司令）
彼得“独行侠”米契尔上校
Captain Pete "Maverick" Mitchell.
你的声名远播
Your reputation precedes you.
谢谢你，长官
Thank you sir.
那不是赞美
Wasn't a compliment.
我是博尔辛普森中将
I'm Admiral Beau Simpson.
航管指挥官，你认识贝兹少将
I'm the Air Boss. I believe you know Admiral Bates.
术士，长官
Warlock sir.
我没想到会受邀回来
Must admit I wasn't expecting an invitation back.
这叫做命令，独行侠
They're called orders Maverick.
你们俩有个共通点
You two have something in common.
旋风是1988届的第一名
Cyclone here was first in his class back in '88.
其实我只是第二名
Actually sir I finished second.
别对我期望太高
Just want to manage expectations.
目标…
The target...
是一座违反多方北约协定
is an unsanctioned uranium enrichment plant
未经批准的铀浓缩工厂
built in violation of a multilateral NATO treaty.
制造的铀对该地区的盟国
The uranium produced there represents a direct threat
造成直接威胁
to our allies in the region.
国防部要求我们召集攻击小队
The Pentagon has tasked us with
assembling a strike team and taking it out
在工厂运作前摧毁它
before it becomes fully operational.
工厂建在位于这座峡谷尽头的地下碉堡
The plant sits in an underground bunker
at the end of this valley.
那座峡谷无法以GPS定位
Said valley is GPS-jammed
也受到多座地对空飞弹炮台防卫
and defended by an extensive surface-to-air missile array
加上数架第五代战斗机
serving a limited number of fifth-generation fighters
以及多架储备战机保卫领空
which in turn are backed up by
a plentiful reserve of surplus aircraft.
包括几架老旧的F-14战机
Even a few old F-14s.
不是只有我们保留了老古董
Seems like we're not the only ones holding on to old relics.
上校，你有什么想法？
What's your read Captain?
通常出动F-35匿踪战机就能搞定
Well sir normally this would be
a cakewalk for the F-35's stealth
但无法以GPS定位就没辙
but the GPS-jamming negates that.
地对空飞弹的存在只能用…
And a surface-to-air threat necessitates
a low-level laser-guided strike
F-18以低空雷射引导攻击
tailor-made for the F-18.
我认为…
I figure
最少要投掷两枚精准炸弹
two precision bombs minimum.
两架一组，出动四架战机
Makes it four aircraft flying in pairs.
飞离峡谷必须垂直爬升
That is one hell of a steep climb out of there
暴露在地对空飞弹攻击范围内
exposing you to all the surface-to-air missiles.
就算成功爬升
You survive that
回程也得一路和敌机交战
it's a dogfight all the way home.
你拥有这一切的实战经验
All requirements for which you have real-world experience.
并不全在同一项任务中
Not in the same mission sir.
不
No.
有人会无法活着回来
No someone's not coming back from this.
到底可不可行？
Can it be done or not?
工厂几时会开始运作？
How soon before the plant becomes operational?
三周后，也许更早
Three weeks. Maybe less.
我很久没开F-18战机，而且…
Well it's been a while since I've flown an F-18 and...
我不确定能信任另外三名飞行员
I'm not sure who I'd trust to fly the other three.
但我会想出办法
But I'll find a way to make it work.
你误会了，上校
I think you misunderstand Captain.
长官？
Sir?
我们不要你飞，而是要你当教官
We don't want you to fly it. We want you to teach it.
教官？
Teach sir?
我们召回十二名扞卫小组毕业学员
We've recalled 12 TOPGUN graduates from their squadrons.
你要从中细选出六名飞行员
We want you to narrow that pool down to six.
让他们执行任务
They'll fly the mission.
上校，有问题吗？
Is there a problem Captain?
你明知道有…长官
You know there is sir.
是啊
Yeah.
布莱德利布雷德萧，也就是公鸡
Bradley Bradshaw aka "Rooster."
你和他老爸曾是搭档
I understand you used to fly with his old man.
他的呼号是什么？
What was his call sign?
“呆头鹅”，长官
"Goose" sir.
他的死是很不幸
Tragic what happened.
米契尔上校被裁定没犯错
Captain Mitchell was cleared of any wrongdoing.
呆头鹅的死是意外
Goose's death was an accident.
你是这么想吗？
Is that how you see it Captain?
呆头鹅的儿子也是这么想吗？
Is that how Goose's son sees it?
恕我直言，长官，我不是教官
With all due respect sir I'm not a teacher.
你当过扞卫小组教官
You were a TOPGUN instructor before.
那是三十年前，只撑了两个月
That was almost 30 years ago. I lasted two months.
我不属于那里
It's not where I belong.
我就老实跟你说吧
Then let me be perfectly blunt.
你不是我的首选，其实根本不在名单上
You were not my first choice.
In fact you weren't even on the list.
举荐你的人是卡赞斯基上将
You are here at the request of Admiral Kazansky.
我非常景仰冰人
Now Iceman happens to be a man I deeply admire
他认为你对海军仍能有所贡献
and he seems to think that
you have something left to offer the navy.
我想不出是什么
What that is I can't imagine.
你不必接下这工作
You don't have to take this job.
但恕我直言
But let me be clear:
这会是你最后一项任务
This will be your last post Captain.
当学校的教官，不然就退出海军
You fly for TOPGUN or you don't fly for the navy ever again.
我赌20块你不能正中红心三次
Twenty bucks you can't get three in a row.
（冰人：“怎么搞得这么僵？”）
（那个孩子还没能准备好执行这项任务）
（冰人：“没有人能
所以才会把你找来”）
（你可以先警告我）
（冰人：“讲了你还会来吗？”）
真不敢相信
Oh you've got to be kidding me.
彼得
Pete.
潘妮？
Penny?
-你在这里干嘛？
-我才要问你呢
-What are you doing here?
-I should ask you the same thing.
-说来话长
-我不信
-Well that is a long story.
-I doubt that.
Yeah.
你这次又惹毛了谁？
Who'd you piss off this time?
另一位少将
Another admiral.
那就对了
Exactly.
-你还在生我气吗？
-彼得
-Are you mad at me?
-Oh Pete.
我没办法一直生你气，那就是问题
I can never stay mad at you. That's the problem.
我得说…
I got to say
我以为永远不会在北岛航空站碰到你
North Island is the one place
I thought for sure I'd never run into you.
-你来了多久？
-三年前顶下这地方
-How long you been here?
-Bought this place about three years ago.
-三年前？
-是啊
-Three years?
-Yeah.
就在你惹毛另一位少将被派去沙漠之后
Not long after you got shipped off to the desert
for pissing off that other admiral.
那是三年前的事？
That was three years ago?
你一定惹上大麻烦
You must be in a lot of trouble.
否则不会自愿回来这里
No way you'd come back here willingly.
不过呢…
Well
你会想办法解决
you'll sort it out.
不，我想…
No I think...
-这是最后一次
-少来了
-I think this is it.
-Come on Pete.
我认识你以后你就一直这么说
You've been saying that as long as I've known you.
你开F-18载我兜风被逮到也这么说
You said it after they busted you
for taking me on a joyride in that F-18.
没过多久你就被派去波士尼亚
Then the next thing I know you're off to Bosnia.
然后去伊拉克，两次都有去
Then Iraq. Both times.
你每次惹上麻烦…
You get yourself in trouble
只要冰人打通电话你又能飞
Iceman makes a call and you're back in the air.
潘妮，这次不同
Penny this is different.
彼得，相信我
Pete trust me
也许现在看似不可能
as improbable as it seems right now
但你一定会再坐上战机出任务
somehow you'll be back in a fighter plane
with your tail on fire.
-潘妮…
-太迟了
-Penny...
-Too late.
什么？
What?
你本来要问我几点下班
You were about to ask me what time I get off.
别用那副表情看我
Don't give me that look.
我没用什么表情看你，我发誓
I'm not giving you any look. I swear.
我们每次的结局都一样，彼得
It always ends the same with us Pete.
这次就别再来一次
Let's not start this time.
好吧
Okay.
很好
你看起来挺好的
You look good.
多谢了，老兄
Much appreciated pal.
发生什么事？
What am I missing?
（冒犯女士、海军，或把手机放吧台 就得请一轮酒）
“冒犯女士、海军，或把手机放吧台
"Disrespect a lady the navy or
put your cell phone on my bar..."
就得请一轮酒”
"...and you buy a round."
请每一个人？
For everyone?
这就是规矩，幸好时候还早
I'm afraid rules are rules. You're lucky it's early.
拜托！
Oh come on!
看看谁来了？
What do we have here?
原来是凤凰
If it ain't Phoenix!
我还以为我们全是菁英，郊狼
And here I thought we were special Coyote.
没想到连逊咖都被找来
Turns out the invite went to anyone.
大伙儿，这是捕手
Fellas this here's Bagman.
-刽子手
-随便你
-Hangman.
-Whatever.
他可是唯一一名海军飞行员
You're looking at the only naval aviator on active duty
曾在空战击落敌机
with a confirmed air-to-air kill.
别说了
Stop.
不过对方开的是韩战时期的古董战机
Mind you the other guy was in a museum piece
from the Korean War.
-冷战
-不同的战争，同一个世纪
-Cold War.
-Different wars same century.
不是这个世纪
Not this one.
你朋友是谁？
Who are your friends?
-复仇者
-粉弟
-Payback.
-Fanboy.
-嘿，郊狼
-嘿
-Hey Coyote.
-Hey.
-他是谁？
-谁是谁？
-Who's he?
-Who's who?
你几时进来的？
When did you get in?
我一直都在这里
I've been here the whole time.
-他开匿踪战机
-他能隐形
-The man's a stealth pilot.
-Literally.
我是武器系统操作官
Weapons systems officer actually.
毫无幽默感
With no sense of humor.
他们叫你什么？
What do they call you?
巴布
Bob.
你的呼号啦
No your call sign.
巴布
Bob.
巴布佛洛伊德
Bob Floyd.
你就是我新的武器官？
You're my new backseater? From Lemoore?
看来是这样，对啊
Looks like it. Yeah.
打一场撞球
Nine-ball Bob.
把球排好
Rack 'em.
好吧
Okay.
-亲爱的潘妮
-是
-Penny my dear.
-Yeah.
再来四杯啤酒，老头子请客
I'll have four more on the old-timer.
布雷德萧
Bradshaw!
是你吗？
Is that you?
原来你回美国啦？
This is how I find out you're stateside?
对啊，我想给你个惊喜
Yeah I just thought I'd surprise you.
我也给你个惊喜
I guess I surprised you back.
-见到你真好
-我也是
-It's good to see you.
-Good to see you too.
-来吧
-谢谢
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
谢啦，老爹
Much appreciated Pops.
趁人少的时候帮我结帐吧
How about ringing me up before the evening rush?
布雷德萧
Bradshaw.
没想到你会来
As I live and breathe.
刽子手
Hangman.
你看起来…还不赖
You look... good.
我是很厉害，公鸡
Well I am good Rooster.
我超厉害的
I'm very good.
老实说
In fact
我厉害到没人信
I am too good to be true.
所以…
So
有人知道为什么把我们找回来吗？
anybody know what this special detachment is all about?
任务就是任务，我不问为什么
No mission's a mission. They don't confront me.
我只想知道，谁会是队长？
What I want to know: Who's gonna be team leader?
又有哪几个够资格跟我出任务？
And which one of y'all has what it takes to follow me?
刽子手，跟你只会提早进棺材
Hangman the only place you'll lead anyone is an early grave.
跟你只会…耗尽燃油
Well anyone who follows you is just gonna run out of fuel.
你就像只公鸡，对吧？
But that's just you ain't it Rooster?
只会窝在驾驶舱
You're snug on that perch
等着永远都不会来的…
waiting for just the right moment...
大好机会
that never comes.
我超爱这首歌
I love this song!
他一点都没变
Well he hasn't changed.
是啊，还是老样子
Nope. Sure hasn't.
你们看
Check it out.
又来了一群
More patches.
哈佛、耶鲁、奥马哈，靠，那是费兹
That's Harvard Yale Omaha. Shit that's Fritz.
这是什么任务？
What the hell kind of mission is this?
我们不该问这问题
That's not the question we should be asking.
大家都是顶尖高手
Everyone here is the best there is.
谁能当我们的教官？
Who the hell are they gonna get to teach us?
信用卡刷不过
It's been declined.
你在开玩笑
You're kidding.
大伙儿，来吧
Hey guys. Come on.
我不如付…
How about...
那不够
That won't cover it.
我明天带钱过来
I'll come by tomorrow and bring you the cash.
规矩就是规矩，彼得
I'm afraid rules are rules Pete.
丢出去…丢出去…
Overboard! Overboard!
真假？
Really?
丢出去…丢出去…
Overboard! Overboard!
见到你真好，彼得
Great to see you Pete!
丢出去…丢出去…
Overboard! Overboard!
多谢了，随时再回来
Thanks for the beers! Come back anytime!
你让我意乱神迷，神魂颠倒
You shake my nerves And you rattle my brain
太多的爱让人精神错乱
Too much love drives a man insane
你害我理智断线，欣喜若狂
You broke my will but what a thrill
爱就像一团大大的火球
Goodness gracious great balls of fire!
我嘲笑爱情，以为那很可笑
I laughed at love 'Cause I thought it was funny
但你姗姗而来，打动我的心
But you came along and you moved me honey
令我领悟到，爱情的美好
I changed my mind this love is fine
爱就像是一团大大的火球
Goodness gracious great balls of fire!
吻我吧，宝贝
Kiss me baby
爱就像是一团大大的火球
Goodness gracious great balls of fire!
高度八千英尺…七千英尺
Altitude 8000... 7000...
呆头鹅，我抓不到弹射手把
Goose I can't reach the ejection handle.
弹射…弹射…
Eject eject eject!
呆头鹅！不！
Goose! Oh no!
他真的很爱跟你飞行，独行侠
God he loved flying with you Maverick.
立正！
Attention on deck!
早安
Morning.
欢迎参加特训营
Welcome to your special training detachment.
坐下来
Be seated.
我是贝兹少将，航空作战中心指挥官
I'm Admiral Bates NAWDC commander.
你们都是扞卫小组毕业生
You're all TOPGUN graduates.
顶尖飞行员
The elite.
菁英中的菁英
The best of the best.
那是过去式
That was yesterday.
敌人全新的第五代战机赶上我们
The enemy's new fifth-generation
fighter has leveled the playing field.
细节不多，但要知道
Details are few but you can be sure
我们不再拥有科技的优势
we no longer possess the technological advantage.
获胜的关键
Success now more than ever
取决于驾驶舱内的男女飞行员
comes down to the man or woman in the box.
你们有一半会入选
Half of you will make the cut.
其中一个会是任务队长
One of you will be named mission leader.
另一半则是储备飞官
The other half will remain in reserve.
你们的教官是你们的学长
Your instructor is a TOPGUN graduate
他拥有你们必须掌握这次任务的
with real-world experience in every mission aspect
实战经验技巧
you will be expected to master.
他的丰功伟业是传奇事蹟
His exploits are legendary.
而且是这项计划有史以来
And he's considered to be one of the finest pilots
训练出来最优秀的飞行员
this program has ever produced.
他能够教导你们的
What he has to teach you
极可能会关乎你们的生死
may very well mean the difference between life and death.
容我介绍彼得米契尔上校
I give you Captain Pete Mitchell.
呼号是独行侠
Call sign: "Maverick."
早安
Good morning.
F-18战机训练及标准操作程序
The F-18 NATOPS.
包含了你们应该知道的一切
It contains everything they want you
to know about your aircraft.
我猜你们都背得滚瓜烂熟
I'm assuming you know the book inside and out.
-没错
-一定要的
-Damn right.
-Damn straight.
你说得对
You got it.
敌人也都知道
So does your enemy.
他又来了
And we're off.
敌人不知道的…是你们的极限
But what the enemy doesn't know is your limits.
我打算找到它们
I intend to find them
测试它们
test them
逼你们超越极限
push beyond.
今天就先从…你们自以为知道的开始
Today we'll start with what you only think you know.
让我看看你们的能耐
You show me what you're made of.
公鸡
Rooster.
布雷德利
Bradley.
布雷德萧中尉
Lieutenant Bradshaw!
是，长官
Yes sir.
我们之间没必要这样
Let's not do it like this.
你会把我刷下来吗？
You gonna wash me out?
那要看你，不是看我
That'll be up to you not me.
我可以走了吗？
Am I dismissed?
早安，飞行员，我是你们的上校
Good morning aviators. This is your captain speaking.
欢迎参加基本飞行训练
Welcome to basic fighter maneuvers.
今天要演练空中缠斗
As briefed today's exercise is dogfighting.
只用机关枪，不用飞弹
Guns only no missiles.
限低不能低于五千尺
We do not go below the hard deck of 5000 feet.
两架战机一组，将我击落，否则…
Working as a team you have to shoot me down or else.
-否则怎样？
-我会反击
-Or else what sir?
-Or else I shoot back.
只要击落一架战机，两架都算输
If I shoot either one of you down you both lose.
这家伙太臭屁了
This guy needs an ego check.
我们会让他吃瘪
We'll see to that.
-不如来赌一把
-你想赌什么？
-What say we put some skin in the game?
-What do you have in mind?
先被击落做两百下伏地挺身
Whoever gets shot down first has to do 200 push-ups.
大伙儿，很多下耶
Guys. That's a lot of push-ups.
训练不是叫假的，长官
They don't call it an exercise for nothing sir.
那就一言为定
You got yourself a deal gentlemen.
开战了，拼了啦
Fight's on. Let's turn and burn.
粉弟，看到他吗？
Fanboy you see him?
他不在前方，一定在后面
Nothing on radar up ahead. He must be somewhere behind us.
-可恶
-搞什么？
-Damn it!
-What the hell?
该死！
Shit!
别这么冲，独行侠
Easy Maverick.
别在第一天就被炒鱿鱼
Let's try not to get fired on the first day.
看见目标…独行侠逼近，向左急转
Tally tally tally! Maverick's coming in! Break left!
向左急转
Breaking left.
复仇者，你的僚机呢？
Payback where's your wingman?
-公鸡，你在哪？
-我会罩你
-Rooster where are you?
-I got your back.
我来了，撑着点，撑着点
I'm coming. Hang in there. Hang in there.
快点，兄弟！快点
Hurry up man! Hurry up!
-复仇者，向右急转
-向右急转
-Payback break right.
-Breaking right.
公鸡救了你们，但他会付出代价
Rooster just saved your life fellas. But it's gonna cost him.
这次不会，老头
Not this time old man.
别被他激怒，独行侠
Don't let him get to you Maverick.
公鸡，你飞得太低，快爬升 你快到限低了
Rooster you're too low! Pull up! You're hitting the hard deck!
-高度，高度
-惨了
-Altitude. Altitude.
-Oh shit.
你被击落了
That's a kill.
伏低，109下
Down! 109.
伏低，110下
Down! 110.
那应该是我们
That should be us down there.
但并不是
But it's not.
现在你们也知道公鸡会牺牲自己
And now you know a little something about Rooster.
留守在跑道，等我们回来
Hold that tarmac down till we get back brother all right?
拍一张，大伙儿
Get in there boys.
-你被击落了
-靠
-That's a kill.
-Damn!
-你死了
-可恶
-Smoked.
-Damn it.
刚才自拍得很爽嘛，伏低
It was all fun and games in that selfie wasn't it? Down!
嘿，凤凰
Say Phoenix.
不如告诉大家“巴布”是别的小名
How's about we tell everybody "Bob" stands for something?
-不只是罗勃特
-别上当
-Other than Robert I mean.
-Don't take the bait Bob.
想知道他为什么叫刽子手吗？
Want to know why we call him Hangman?
我想到了，“巴布叭噗”
I got it. "Baby On Board."
靠！
Shit!
各位飞官好，开战了
Greetings aviators. Fight's on.
凤凰，把这家伙击落
All right Phoenix let's take this guy out!
小心后方，凤凰
Watch your back Phoenix.
-向右急转
-Break right!
-Breaking right.
他去哪儿？
Where's he going?
他是刽子手，只会害死你
That's why we call him Hangman.
He'll always hang you out to dry.
丢下你的僚机
Leaving your wingman.
很久没看过这一招了
There's a strategy I haven't seen in a while.
他在笑你，你忍得了吗？
He called you a man Phoenix. You gonna take that?
只要他当你就忍得了
So long as he doesn't call you a man.
巴布，独行侠在哪？
Talk to me Bob. Where's Maverick?
天啊，他已经绕回来了！
Jesus his nose is already coming around!
帮我甩掉他，刽子手
Get him off me Hangman!
各位听众，我要埋了这化石
For all you folks at home this is how you bury a fossil.
刽子手，该教训你了
All right Hangman. Time to teach you a lesson.
-你挂了，凤凰
-混蛋
-You're out Phoenix.
-Son of a bitch!
开战了
That's it.
-来吧，独行侠，看你有多厉害
-来追我啊
-Let's go Mav. Let's see what you got.
-Come get me.
恶魔散退，刽子手来也
Evil be gone. Hangman's coming.
我得承认，你很行
Yeah you're good. I'll give you that.
靠，看不到他，我离他多近？
Shit. Phoenix I can't see him. How close am I?
-凤凰？
-我挂了，猪头
-Phoenix?
-I'm dead dickhead.
下辈子再见，捕手
See you in the afterlife Bagman.
他在哪？他在哪？
Where is he? Where is he?
你死了
That's a kill.
79，伏低，80，伏低
Seventy-nine. Down. Eighty. Down.
开战吧，下一个是谁？
Let's go. Who's next?
-击中你了，奥马哈
-可恶
-I got you Omaha.
-Damn it!
-你死了，郊狼
-收到
-Lights out Coyote.
-Copy kill.
伏低，51，伏低，52
Down. Fifty-one. Down. Fifty-two.
公鸡，能问个私人问题吗？
So Rooster mind if I ask you a personal question?
我能说不能吗？
Would it matter if I did?
你和独行侠有什么过节？
What's the story with you and Maverick?
-你好像跟他过不去
-不关你的事
-It seems like he's got you rattled.
-That's none of your business.
他到底在哪里？
Now where the hell is he?
一直都在这里
Been here the whole time.
哇哩咧
Holy shit.
看到我了吗？
You see me now?
来吧，速战速决
Come on let's get it over with.
开战了
Fight's on!
那两个人到底是怎么回事？
What is with these two?
你逼我们盘旋俯冲，要怎么解套？
All right you put us here. How you gonna get yourself out?
你随时都能撤
You can bail out anytime.
公鸡，你想俯冲到多低？
How low you want to go Rooster?
比你更低，你懂我意思
I can go as low as you sir! And that's saying something.
过去的就让它过去
What's past is past. For both of us.
你很想，对吧？
You'd like to believe that wouldn't you?
限低是五千尺，就快到了
Hard deck is 5000 feet fellas. You are running out of room.
高度
Altitude.
你打算害我们都坠机
Your strategy is about to run us into the ground.
-你想怎样？
-高度…
-What's your move?
-Altitude. Altitude.
高度
Altitude.
高度…高度…
Altitude. Altitude. Altitude.
高度，高度
Altitude. Altitude.
爬升…爬升…
Pull up! Pull up! Pull up! Pull up!
Pull up! Pull up!
你行的，别犹豫，放手去做
You got it. Don't think just do.
你逮到他了，飞低然后射击
Come on Rooster you got him! Drop down and take the shot!
太低了
It's too low.
太迟了，你错过机会
Too late. You had your chance.
你被击落，玩完了
That's a kill. Knock it off.
可恶
Damn it!
还是老样子
Same old Rooster.
去找宏多做伏地挺身
Go see Hondo about your push-ups.
好了，够了
All right that's enough.
公鸡，够了
Rooster. That's enough man.
违纪抗命，你想被踢走吗？
Breaking the hard deck insubordination.
Are you trying to get kicked out?
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我想要出这项任务
Look I'm going on this mission.
但你被踢走，我就得和刽子手合作
But if you get kicked out you leave us flying with Hangman.
-那是怎么回事？
-他拿掉我的文件
-Talk to me. What the hell was that?
-He pulled my papers.
-什么？谁？
-独行侠
-What? Who?
-Maverick.
他拿掉我海军官校的申请书
He pulled my application to the Naval Academy.
害我浪费了四年
Set me back four years.
他为什么要这么做？
Why would he do that?
限低是五千尺
The hard deck is 5000 feet above ground level.
不只是为了飞行员的安全
A parameter is set not just for the safety of our pilots
也是为了战机的安全
but for the safety of their aircraft.
五千尺不只是规定，更是一条铁律
5000 feet is not just a rule.
It is a law as immutable as gravity.
这项任务的限低会更低
The hard deck will be much lower for the mission sir.
没我的允许不准更改
And it will not change without my approval!
尤其是在演练空战的时候
Especially not in the middle of an exercise.
你那招眼镜蛇机动会害死你们三个
And that Cobra maneuver of yours?
That could've got all three of you killed.
我不想再看到那种屁事
I never want to see that shit again.
你以为你在教什么？
What exactly do you suppose you were teaching Captain?
他们虽然很优秀，但还有得要学
That as good as they are sir
they still have something to learn.
他们是世上最顶尖的飞行员
You are talking about the best fighter pilots
on the planet Captain.
他们一直都被吹捧
And they've been told that their entire career
却只会从高空投掷炸弹
while they've been dropping bombs from a high altitude
没有空战的经验
with little to no dogfighting.
这是他们从来没有执行过的任务
The parameters of this mission call for something
they have never encountered.
你只有不到三周要教会他们团队合作
Okay you have less than three weeks
to teach them how to fight as a team
还有击中目标
and how to strike the target.
也要活着回来
And how to come home.
必须活着回来，长官
And how to come home sir.
每项任务都有风险
Every mission has its risks.
这些飞行员都能接受
These pilots accept that.
我不接受，长官
I don't sir.
从今天起，每天早上
Every morning from this day forward
你要书面报告你的教战计划
you will brief us on your instructional plans in writing.
没有我的允许不准做出更动
And nothing will change without my express approval.
-包括限低？
-尤其是限低，上校
-Including the hard deck sir?
-Especially the hard deck Captain.
长官
Sir.
这是什么？
What is this?
要求降低限低，长官
It's a request to lower the hard deck sir
为了演练低空轰炸任务
to practice a low-level bombing
run per the mission parameters.
有关时机的掌控要多注意点，上校
You could learn a thing or two about timing Captain.
唷，郊狼
Yo Coyote.
你看看
Take a look at this.
传奇人物，就是他
The man the legend. There he is.
不是啦，他旁边那个
No no no. Next to him.
很眼熟吧？
He look familiar to you?
这什么情况？
What have we here?
（布雷德萧）
布雷德萧
Bradshaw.
我不敢相信
As I live and breathe.
弟欧…你长大了
Hey Theo you got big.
嘿，独行侠
Hey Mav.
艾蜜莉雅？
Amelia?
我知道，我长大了
I know. I got big.
是啊
Yes.
酒吧五点才开
Bar opens at 5:00.
我只是来还钱的
No I just came by to pay off a debt.
妈！
Mom!
-你爸好吗？
-跟他老婆在夏威夷
-Hey how's your dad?
-With his wife in Hawaii.
妈！
Mom!
独行侠说他欠你钱
Mav says he owes you money.
-没关系啦
-我坚持
-Don't worry about it.
-I insist.
谢了，上校，酒帐还清了
Thank you Captain. Consider your tab closed.
还是上校？
Captain? Still?
战功彪炳的上校
A highly decorated captain.
做完功课
Finish up.
得把帆船开到船坞
We have to get the boat to the yard.
-我不行
-什么意思？
-I can't go.
-What do you mean you can't go?
明天要抽考，我得用功念书 他们今天才通知我们
Test tomorrow. I have to study. They only told us today.
我不能一个人驾船
Well I can't sail her alone.
用引擎啊
Just use the engine.
为什么要开到船坞？
Why are we taking her to the yard?
修理引擎
To fix the engine.
我能帮忙
I can help.
-浪比我预期的更大
-还用说
-Little rougher than I was expecting.
-You don't say.
拉住控帆索，减低风力
Pull on the backstay. We'll de-power the sails.
好啊
Okay.
那什么意思？
What does that mean?
你是海军耶
You're supposed to be in the navy!
我不会航船，只会降落在航母
I don't sail boats Penny. I land on them.
这就像打开襟翼一样
It's sort of like raising the flaps on an airplane.
我要怎么做？
So how do I do that?
拉住那条绿绳索
You pull on that green line up there.
绿绳索
Green line.
对，用力拉
Yep. Pull it hard.
很好，用力转那个曲柄
Yep. Crank that winch right there
拉紧三角帆
tighten the jib.
-用力转，还行吗？
-行
-Crank it. You okay?
-Yeah.
很好
Good.
现在…
Now
准备好了吗？
you ready?
准备好什么？
For what?
拉起风帆
The afterburner.
现在你才算是海军
Now you're in the navy.
今天谢谢你帮忙
Thanks for helping out today.
我好像没帮到什么
I'm not exactly sure I helped.
别那副表情
Don't give me that look.
什么表情？
What look?
那副表情
That one.
晚安，彼得
Good night Pete.
晚安，潘妮
Night Penny.
妈，是你吗？
Mom is that you?
对啊
Yeah it's me.
我替你做晚饭
I'll make you dinner.
Okay.
（抵达目标时间：三分钟）
时间…是最大的敌人
Time is your greatest enemy.
任务第一阶段是低空进入
Phase one of the mission will be a low-level ingress
两架战机一组进行攻击
attacking in two-plane teams.
沿着狭窄的峡谷飞至目标
You'll fly along this narrow canyon to your target.
雷达导引地对空飞弹防卫该地区
Radar-guided surface-to-air missiles defend the area.
这些飞弹…极度致命
These SAMs they're lethal.
但它们负责防御领空，不是峡谷
But they were designed to protect the skies above
not the canyon below.
因为敌人知道没人会疯狂到飞进峡谷
That's because the enemy knows
no one is insane enough to try and fly below them.
我就是要训练你们这么做
That's exactly what I'm gonna train you to do.
任务当天的飞行高度最多100尺
On the day your altitude will be 100 feet maximum.
超过这高度就会被雷达侦测…
You exceed this altitude radar will spot you
你就死定了
and you're dead.
飞行速度是660节…
Your airspeed will be 660 knots
最低速度
minimum.
抵达目标时间是两分半钟
Time to target: two and a half minutes.
因为第五代战机在附近军用机场待命
That's because fifth-generation
fighters wait at an air base nearby.
F-18战机对上它们…必死无疑
In a head-to-head with these planes in your F-18s you're dead.
你们得飞进峡谷，击中目标
That's why you need to get in hit your target and be gone
趁那些战机尚未抵达时飞离敌区
before these planes even have a chance of catching you.
时间就变得至关重要
This makes time your greatest adversary.
你们要照着模拟峡谷的航道飞行
You'll fly a route in your nav
system that simulates the canyon.
越快飞过峡谷
The faster you navigate this canyon
越不会被敌军雷达侦测
the harder it'll be to stay under
the radar of these enemy SAMs.
弯度越窄
The tighter the turns
身体承受的G力就越大
the more intensely the force of gravity
on your body multiplies
肺部受到挤压
compressing your lungs
血液离开大脑
forcing the blood from your brain
减低判断及反应时间
impairing your judgment and reaction time.
今天的训练比较轻松
So for today's lesson we're gonna take it easy on you.
高度三百尺，目标时间三分钟
Max ceiling: 300 feet. Time to target: three minutes.
祝好运
Good luck.
目标时间一分半钟
Time to target is one minute 30.
我们落后两秒，加速到480节
We are two seconds behind. Increase to 480 knots.
我们得快点，郊狼
We got to move Coyote.
收到，加速中
Copy. Increasing speed.
噢，靠
Oh shit!
他们怎么会死？
Why are they dead?
我们超过300尺 一枚地对空飞弹击落我们
We broke the 300-foot ceiling and a SAM took us out.
不对，他们怎么会死？
No. Why are they dead?
我减速却没警告她，是我的错
I slowed down and didn't give her a warning. It was my fault.
你为什么没警告队友？
Was there a reason you didn't communicate with your team?
我正在专心…
I was focusing on--
说出家属在葬礼能接受的理由
One that their family will accept at the funeral.
我没有，长官
None sir.
你熟知地形，怎么不知道要急转？
Why didn't you anticipate the turn?
You were briefed on the terrain.
别告诉我，告诉他的家属
Don't tell me. Tell it to his family.
刽子手，慢点，峡谷越来越窄
Hangman ease up. The canyon's getting tighter.
不行，复仇者，你要加速
Negative Payback. Increase your speed.
-你飞得太快
-提早达标是好事
-You're going too fast man.
-No harm in being ahead of schedule.
快减速，我无法留在航道
Damn it slow down! I can't stay on the course!
你会撞上山壁，小心…
You're gonna hit the wall! Watch out! Watch out!
-怎么回事？
-我飞到最快
-What happened?
-I flew as fast as I could.
像是火烧屁股一样
Kind of like my ass depended on it.
你危及到队友，僚机也挂了
And you put your team in danger and your wingman's dead.
他们跟不上我
They couldn't keep up.
公鸡，我们落后20秒
Rooster we're 20 seconds behind and dropping.
没问题，速度可以
We're fine. Speed is good.
加速到500节
Increase to 500 knots.
-不，耶鲁，别加速
-我们落后了
-Negative Yale. Hold your speed.
-Rooster we're late!
我们还活着，直飞时再赶进度
We're alive. We'll make up time in the straightaway.
我们会来不及
We are not gonna make it.
相信我，保持速度，赶得到的
Just trust me. Maintain your speed. We can make it.
你为什么会死？
Why are you dead?
你是队长，队友为什么会死？
You're team leader up there.
Why are you why is your team dead?
长官，只有他抵达目标
Sir he's the only one who made it to the target.
迟了一分钟
A minute late.
他给敌机时间击落他
He gave enemy aircraft time to shoot him down.
-他死了
-你不能确定
-He is dead.
-You don't know that.
你飞得太慢，浪费了时间
You're not flying fast enough.
You don't have a second to waste.
我们成功抵达目标
We made it to the target.
更优越的敌机在返航时拦截你
And superior enemy aircraft intercepted you on your way out.
-那就展开空战
-对上第五代战机
-Then it's a dogfight.
-Against fifth-generation fighters.
-还是有机会
-F-18战机赢不了
-Yeah. We'd still have a chance.
-In an F-18.
关键不是在战机…而是飞行员
It's not the plane sir it's the pilot.
一点也没错
Exactly!
执行这任务有别的方法
There's more than one way to fly this mission.
你真的没搞懂
You really don't get it.
执行这任务就得像独行侠那样飞
On this mission a man flies like Maverick here
否则就不可能回来
or a man does not come back.
无意冒犯
No offense intended.
但你却老是惹毛我们
Yet somehow you always manage.
我不是批评你，只是你太保守了
Look I don't mean to criticize.
You're conservative that's all.
中尉
Lieutenant.
我们将进行…没有飞行员尝试过的空战
We're going into combat son
on a level no living pilot's ever seen.
就连他也没有过
Not even him.
没时间纠结过去的事
That's no time to be thinking about the past.
-那是什么意思？
-公鸡
-What's that supposed to mean?
-Rooster.
大家都知道他老爸和独行侠一起飞过
I can't be the only one that knows
that Maverick flew with his old man.
-够了
-或者是独行侠
-That's enough.
-Or that Maverick was flying
-害死他老爸…
-中尉，够了！
-when his old man--
-Lieutenant that's enough!
-够了
-你这王八蛋
-That's enough.
-You son of a bitch!
嘿，别这样！
Hey come on!
我没事，嘿嘿嘿
I'm cool I'm cool. Hey hey hey.
够了
That's enough.
-他不够资格出任务
-够了
-He's not cut out for this mission.
-That's enough!
你明明知道
You know it.
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
全员解散
You're all dismissed.
（冰人：“我得见你”）
（不太方便）
（冰人：“我没在问你”）
独行侠
Maverick.
又复发了？
It's come back?
没人知道
No one knows.
医生也无能为力
There's nothing else they can do.
他连说话都很痛苦
Even speaking is painful now.
莎拉，真的很抱歉
Sarah I'm so sorry.
上将
Admiral.
我的僚机驾驶员还好吗？
How's my wingman?
（我想谈谈工作）
没事…别替我担心
Please don't worry about me.
我能做什么？
What can I do for you?
（我想谈谈工作）
好吧
All right.
公鸡还在为我做的事生气
Well Rooster's still angry with me about what I did.
我以为他有一天能理解
I thought eventually he would understand why.
也希望他能原谅我
I hoped he'd forgive me.
（还有时间）
任务只剩下不到三礼拜
The mission is less than three weeks away.
那孩子没准备好
The kid's not ready.
（那就教好他）
他不要我教
He doesn't want what I have to give.
冰人，拜托
Ice please
别要求我派别人去赴死
don't ask me to send someone else to die.
别这么做
Please don't...
别要我派他去
Don't ask me to send him.
派我去
Send me.
（该放手了）
我不知道该如何放手
I don't know how.
我不是教官，冰人
I'm not a teacher Ice.
我是战机驾驶员
I'm a fighter pilot.
海军飞行员
A naval aviator.
那不仅仅是工作职称
It's not what I am.
而是我与生俱来的能力
It's who I am.
我该怎么教这种事？
How do I teach that?
就算可以，也不是公鸡要的
Even if I could teach it it's not what Rooster wants.
更不是海军要的
It's not what the navy wants.
所以上次我才会被开除
That's why they canned me the last time.
我之所以还能在海军是因为你
The only reason I'm here is you.
如果我派他出这项任务
If I send him on this mission
他可能就此一去不回
he might never come home.
但若不派他去
And if I don't send him
他绝对不会原谅我
he'll never forgive me.
不管怎样，我都将永远失去他
Either way I could lose him forever.
（该放手了）
我知道
I know.
海军…需要独行侠
The navy needs Maverick.
那孩子需要独行侠
The kid needs Maverick.
这是为什么我极力为你争取
That's why I fought for you.
这也是为什么你仍然在这里
That's why you're still here.
谢谢你，冰人
Thank you Ice
为我所做的一切
for everything.
最后一件事
One last thing.
谁是比较厉害的飞行员？
Who's the better pilot?
你或我？
You or me?
现在气氛正好，别破坏了！
This is a nice moment. Let's not ruin it.
好了…
All right all right.
达阵！
Touchdown!
长官
Sir.
-这算什么？
-美式足球空战
-What is this?
-This is dogfight football.
同时进攻和防守
Offense and defense at the same time.
谁领先？
Who's winning?
他们早就没在计分了
I think they stopped keeping score a while ago.
这批特遣队还需要训练，上校
This detachment still has some training to complete Captain.
-每分每秒都很重要
-是，长官
-Every available minute matters.
-Yes sir.
那为什么还在打球？
So why are we out here playing games?
你说要团队合作，长官
You said to create a team sir.
那就是你的团队
There's your team.
我该趁艾蜜莉雅回来前走吗？
Should I go? Before Amelia gets back?
-她要在朋友家过夜
-那就好
-She'll be at her friend's house tonight.
-Oh good.
你和艾蜜莉雅看起来…
You and Amelia you seem...
比之前更亲密
a lot closer than when I last saw you.
-是啊，是真的
-怎么做到的？
-Yeah. Yeah we are.
-How do you manage?
这个嘛…
Well
你知道的，她一直要我给她更多的自由
you know she always wanted more freedom
than I thought she was ready for.
不知道这一点是遗传到谁？
Where'd she get that from I wonder?
我猜我发现…
I guess I realized
我也必须信任她
I also had to trust her.
偶尔让她自己犯些错
Let her make some of her own mistakes sometimes.
这决定不容易
Not an easy choice.
你和公鸡是怎么回事？
Is that what happened with Rooster?
我拿掉他的海军官校申请书
I pulled his papers from the Naval Academy.
浪费了他几年时间
Took years off his career.
为什么？
Why?
呆头鹅死后，他母亲不希望他当飞官
His mother never wanted him to fly
not after what happened to Goose.
她死前要我答应她，所以…
She made me promise before she died so...
公鸡知道吗？
Does Rooster know that?
他永远会为这件事恨我
He will always resent me for what I did.
没必要让他也恨她
Why should he resent her too?
这决定不容易
Not an easy choice.
我试着当他失去的父亲
I was trying to be the father he lost.
只是…
I just--
我希望能做得更好
I wish I would've done it better.
但是…事实是
But the truth is...
我认为他还没准备好
I didn't think he was ready.
现在呢？
Is he ready now?
妈，我回家了！
Mom I'm home!
我以为你要在凯伦家过夜
I thought you were staying at Karen's tonight.
凯伦生病，我有功课要做
Karen's sick. And I've got homework to do.
-我该走了
-你该走了
-I should go.
-You should go.
-吃过饭吗？
-还没，要出去吃吗？
-Have you had dinner yet?
-Not yet. You want to go out?
没关系，我做给你吃
No it's okay. I'll make you something.
马上就下去
I'll be down in a sec!
-等等，别走那儿
-什么？
-Wait! Not that way.
-What?
我得当个好榜样
Look I have an example to set.
不能第一次约会就带男人回家
I can't be bringing guys home on a first date.
这不是第一次约会
This is not our first date.
你懂我的意思
You know what I mean.
好吧
Okay.
Fine.
这是我最后一次跳出你家窗户
But this is the last time I go out your window.
再说吧
We'll see.
我是说真的
No. No I mean it.
我永远不会再离开你
I'm never gonna leave you again.
闭嘴啦
Oh shut up.
快走吧
Go on get out of here.
别再伤她的心
Just don't break her heart again.
早安
Good morning.
你们的目标铀浓缩工厂
The uranium enrichment plant that is your target
将会提早开始运作
will be operational earlier than expected.
天然铀在十天内会送到工厂
Raw uranium will be delivered to the plant in ten days' time.
所以你们的任务也提前一星期
As a result your mission has been moved up one week
以免那座峡谷受到辐射污染
in order to avoid contaminating
the target valley with radiation.
长官，这里没人成功完成低空航道飞行
Sir no one here has successfully flown a low-level course.
但你们仍被命令继续下去
Nevertheless you've been ordered to move on.
上校
Captain.
只剩一星期进行第二阶段演练
We have one week left to focus on phase two.
那是这项任务最困难的阶段
It's the most difficult stage of the mission.
那是俯冲突袭行动
It's a pop-up strike with a steep dive
需要连续出现两个奇蹟
requiring nothing less than two consecutive miracles.
两组战机要以并列队形飞行
Two pairs of F-18s will fly in a welded wing formation.
团队合作
Teamwork.
飞行的精准度是这项任务成功…
Precise coordination of these aircraft is essential
和你们存活的关键
to both the mission's success and your survival.
工厂坐落在两座山脉之间
As you know the plant rests between two mountains.
逼近时要倒栽葱直接俯冲
On final approach you'll invert directly into a steep dive.
这样才能保持低空飞行
This allows you to maintain the lowest possible altitude
也是唯一的攻击角度
and the only possible attack angle.
目标的弹着点不到三米宽
Your target is an impact point less than three meters wide.
两人座战机将以雷射标示靶点
The two-seat aircraft will paint the target
with a laser bull's-eye.
第一组将发射雷射引导飞弹
The first pair will breach the reactor
进入通风口炸毁反应炉
by dropping a laser-guided bomb
on an exposed ventilation hatch.
这会为第二组制造空档
This will create an opening for the second pair.
那是第一个奇蹟
That's miracle number one.
第二组…
The second team
将做出必杀一击
will deliver the kill shot
彻底摧毁目标
and destroy the target.
那是第二个奇蹟
That's miracle number two.
两组都没有命中目标…
If either team misses the target...
未命中
That's a miss.
-任务就失败
-可恶
-...the mission is a failure.
-Damn it!
飞离时必须垂直爬升，以免撞到山壁
Egress is a steep high-G climb out
to avoid hitting this mountain.
高速垂直爬升至少会承受8个G力
A steep climb at that speed you're pulling at least eight G's.
至少9个G力
Nine minimum.
F-18机身的极限应力是7.5
The stress limit of the F-18's airframe is 7.5.
那是可接受的极限
That's the accepted limit.
想活着回来就得超越极限
To survive this mission you'll pull beyond that
就算必须折弯机身
even if it means bending your airframe.
重力大到你们会重达900公斤
You'll be pulling so hard you'll weigh close to 2000 pounds
头盖骨会挤压脊椎
your skull crushing your spine
像被一头大象坐在胸口挤压肺部
your lungs imploding like an elephant's sitting on your chest
拼了命也要避免昏厥过去
fighting with everything you have just to
keep from blacking out.
这是你们最脆弱的时刻
And this is where you'll be at your most vulnerable.
这就是棺材角
This is Coffin Corner.
就算你们没撞上山壁
Assuming you avoid crashing into this mountain
也会爬升到敌军雷达范围内 同时完全失速
you'll climb straight up into enemy radar
while losing all of your airspeed.
这时候将遇到敌军飞弹攻击
Within seconds you'll be fired upon by enemy SAMs.
你们都承受过G力，但这次…
You've all faced sustained G's before but this--
将把你们和战机逼到临界点
this is gonna take you and
your aircraft to the breaking point.
长官，有可能成功吗？
Sir is this even achievable?
这个问题的答案…
The answer to that question
取决于驾驶舱内的飞行员
will come down to the pilot in the box.
-回报状况，巴布
-我们落后12秒
-Talk to me Bob.
-We are 12 seconds late on target.
-必须加速…
-收到，试着跟上来
-We got to move! We got to move!
-Copy. Try to stay with me.
等等，那是谁？
Wait who's that?
蓝组，你们被侦测到
Blue Team you've been spotted.
-靠，是独行侠
-他跑来干嘛？
-Shit it's Maverick.
-What the hell is he doing here?
我是来拦截的敌机，你们要怎么办？
I'm a bandit on course to intercept.
Blue Team what are you gonna do?
左翼20哩，10点钟方向，700节
He's 20 miles left. Ten o'clock. 700 knots closure.
你决定，你要怎么做？
Your call. What do you want to do?
继续下去，就快接近目标了
Continue. We're close. Stay on target.
-他绕到北方
-准备爬升
-He's swinging around to the north!
-Stand by for pop-up.
-准备雷射引导
-收到
-Be ready on that laser Bob.
-Copy. I'm on it.
蓝组，敌机逼近中
Blue Team bandit is still closing.
爬升
Popping now.
回报状况，巴布，独行侠呢？
Talk to me Bob. Where's Maverick?
他在五哩外，快速逼近
He's five miles out. He's coming fast.
-看到目标
-雷射呢？
-Target's in sight.
-Where's my laser Bob?
无法瞄准…抱歉，无法锁定目标
Deadeye! Deadeye! It's no good. Sorry I can't get a lock.
来不及了，我要盲投炸弹
We're out of time. I'm dropping blind.
该死，没命中
Damn it missed!
-锁定你了
-独行侠的飞弹锁定我们
-That's tone.
-Maverick's got missile lock on us.
靠，我们挂了
Shit! We're dead.
蓝组，任务失败，停止爬升
Blue Team that's a fail. Level out Coyote.
郊狼？收到吗？
Coyote? Do you copy?
郊狼，回答
Coyote come in.
郊狼，拉直
Coyote level wings.
天啊，他进入G力昏迷
Oh God. He's in G-LOC.
郊狼？郊狼？
Coyote? Coyote?
-他会坠机
-我去追他
-He's gonna burn in!
-I'm going after him.
快啊，快点锁定…
Come on. Give me tone give me tone give me tone.
快醒醒，郊狼，快啊…
Snap out of it Coyote. Come on! Come on!
加油，郊狼，快啊，快啊！
Come on Coyote come on. Come on!
-该死，郊狼…
-爬升
-Damn it! Coyote!
-Pull up!
-郊狼…
-爬升…
-Coyote! Coyote!
-Pull up! Pull up!
郊狼，没事吧？
Coyote you okay?
我没事
I'm okay. I'm good.
那就好，今天演练够了
Good. Good. That's enough for today.
好险喔
That was close.
太危险了
Too close.
鸟击！
Bird strike! Bird strike!
Bird strike!
-凤凰，左引擎起火
-爬升
-Phoenix left engine's on fire!
-Climbing.
减速，关闭左引擎燃油
Throttling back. Shutting off fuel to left engine.
灭火
Extinguishing fire.
右引擎故障
Right engine is out!
涡轮还在旋转，试图重新启动
It's still spinning. Trying to restart it.
-凤凰，起火了，别启动
-加速
-Phoenix it's on fire. Don't start it.
-Throttling up.
我的天啊
Oh my God.
-起火了…
-该死
-We're on fire! We're on fire!
-Damn it!
-右引擎起火
-熄灭右引擎
-Engine fire. Right.
-Extinguishing right engine.
凤凰、巴布，快弹跳，快弹跳！
Phoenix Bob punch out punch out!
警示灯都亮着，液压系统失灵
Warning lights everywhere! Hydraulic failure!
-操纵失效
-我无法控制了
-Flight controls.
-I can't control it.
我们要坠机了，凤凰 我们要坠入山谷了…
We're going down Phoenix! We're going in! We're going in!
没救了，快弹跳…
You can't save it. Eject eject!
弹跳…弹跳…
Eject eject eject!
高度，高度
Altitude. Altitude.
凤凰和巴布要在医院过夜接受观察
They'll keep Phoenix and Bob
in the hospital overnight for observation.
他们不会有事
They're gonna be okay.
那就好
That's good.
我从未失去过僚机
I've never lost a wingman.
你很幸运
You're lucky.
飞得够久，就会发生
Fly long enough it'll happen.
会有其他人
There will be others.
你说得倒容易，没有老婆
Easy for you to say. No wife.
没有小孩
No kids.
挂了也不会有人悼念你
Nobody to mourn you when you burn in.
回家吧
Go home.
好好睡个觉吧
Just get some sleep.
你为什么拿掉我官校的申请书？
Why'd you pull my papers at the Academy?
为什么挡我的路？
Why did you stand in my way?
你当时还没准备好
You weren't ready.
准备好什么？
Ready for what?
-像你那样乱飞？
-不
-Ready to fly like you?
-No.
准备忘记书本里的规则
Ready to forget the book.
相信直觉，别犹豫，放手去做
Trust your instincts. Don't think just do.
只要犹豫就会死，相信我
You think up there you're dead. Believe me.
我爸相信你
My dad believed in you.
但我不会犯同样的错
I'm not gonna make the same mistake.
独行侠
Maverick.
预备、瞄准、射击
Ready aim fire.
预备
Ready
瞄准
aim
射击
fire.
预备
Ready
瞄准
aim
射击
fire.
我无法体会你现在的感受
I can only imagine what you must be feeling right now.
想休息几天就休息几天
Take some time. Whatever you need.
谢谢你，长官，但是任务…
I appreciate that sir but there is no time. The mission--
我会接手训练他们
I'll be taking over the training from here.
长官？
Sir?
我们都知道你不想要这工作
We both know you didn't want this job Captain.
-他们还没准备好
-那是你的工作
-Sir they're not ready.
-It was your job to get them ready.
他们必须相信能达成这项任务
Sir they have to believe that this mission can be flown.
你却只让他们认为任务会失败
And all you've managed to do is teach them that it can't.
-长官…
-你被禁飞了
-Sir--
-You're grounded Captain.
永远禁飞
Permanently.
-长官…
-就这样
-Sir--
-That is all.
我听说了
I heard.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
你有什么打算？
What are you gonna do?
冰人走了
Ice is gone.
我还能有什么选择？
What choice do I have?
你会找到继续飞的方法
You'll have to find a way back on your own.
不，潘妮
No Penny.
我已出局
I'm out.
军旅生涯结束了
This is over.
彼得…
Pete.
就算失去你的僚机
If you lost your wingman up there
还是会继续奋战
you'd keep fighting.
不会放弃
You wouldn't just give up.
他们是你的飞行员
Those are your pilots.
要是他们出事…
If anything happens to them
你会永远无法原谅自己
you'll never forgive yourself.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know what to do.
你会找到方法的
But you'll find a way.
你一定会的
I know you will.
米契尔上校不再是你们的教官
Captain Mitchell is no longer your instructor.
从今天起有新的任务参数
And as of today there are new mission parameters.
抵达目标时间是四分钟
Time to target is now four minutes.
你们将减速平飞进入峡谷
You'll be entering the valley level at reduced speed.
不准超过420节
Not to exceed 420 knots.
敌机不就有时间进行拦截？
Sir won't we be giving their planes time to intercept?
对上敌机至少还有机会存活
Well Lieutenant you have a fighting chance
against enemy aircraft.
撞上山壁存活的机率是多少？
What are the odds of surviving a
head-on collision with a mountain?
你们要沿着北边山壁
You'll be attacking the target from a higher altitude
从更高的高度攻击目标
level with the north wall.
这会更难以雷射标示目标
Gonna be a little harder to keep your lase on target
但能避免高G力爬升
but you will avoid the high-G climb out.
敌方飞弹会击落我们
We'll be sitting ducks for enemy missiles.
那是谁？
Who the hell is that?
独行侠呼叫控制中心，进入A点
Maverick to Range Control. Entering Point Alpha.
请确认安全
Confirm green range.
这是控制中心…
Maverick Range Control
确认安全
green range is confirmed.
我没看到你的演练行程
I don't see an event scheduled for you sir.
我还是要去
Well I'm going anyway.
水啦
Nice.
设定目标时间：2分15秒
Setting time to target: Two minutes 15 seconds.
2分15秒？不可能
2:15? That's impossible.
独行侠飞往最终攻击点
Final attack point. Maverick's inbound.
倒数三、二、一，爬升
Popping in three two one.
投掷炸弹
Bombs away.
正中目标！哇靠！
Bull's-eye! Holy shit!
厉害
Yes.
帅
Damn.
你让我左右为难，上校
You have put me in a difficult position Captain.
你一方面示范了任务的可行性
On the one hand you have demonstrated
that this mission can be flown.
也许是唯一存活的方法
Perhaps the only way it can be survived.
另一方面…
On the other hand
你偷开走一架数百万美金的战机
you did it by stealing a
multimillion-dollar military aircraft
把它操到可能永远无法再飞行
and flying it in such a manner
that it may never be airworthy again.
冰人不能再保护你了
Iceman is no longer here to protect you.
我大可以把你送去军事法庭
I have everything I need to have you court-martialed
让你不荣誉退伍
and dishonorably discharged.
我该怎么做？
So what do I do?
冒着飞行员阵亡和任务失败的风险
Risk the lives of my pilots and
perhaps the success of this mission
或是
or...
拿我的军旅生涯赌一把
risk my career
任命你为任务队长？
by appointing you team leader?
长官…
Sir--
中将只是问问而已，上校
I think the admiral's asking a rhetorical question Captain.
该怎么办？呆头鹅
Talk to me Goose.
米契尔上校
Captain Mitchell!
你属于这里
You're where you belong.
让我们以你为荣
Make us proud.
很荣幸能与你们飞行
It has been an honor flying with you.
每一位都是菁英中的菁英
Each one of you represents the best of the best.
这项任务非常艰钜
This is a very specific mission.
我的选择完全是针对任务
My choice is a reflection of that and nothing more.
挑选两组F小队队员
Choose your two Foxtrot teams.
复仇者和粉弟
Payback and Fanboy.
凤凰和巴布
Phoenix and Bob.
你的僚机驾驶员
And your wingman.
公鸡
Rooster.
其他人在航母待命
The rest of you will stand by on the carrier
随时准备支援
for any reserve role that's required.
解散
Dismissed.
你们的目标是迫切的威胁
Your target is a clear and present threat.
受到敌国掌控的秘密铀浓缩工厂
A secret uranium enrichment site under rogue state control.
位于地下碉堡
It's an underground bunker
坐落在这两座山脉之间
tucked between these two mountains.
进攻航道受到多个防空炮台防卫
Your route of ingress is heavily
defended by surface-to-air missiles
另有第五代战机支援
backed up by fifth-generation fighters.
F-18攻击小队一旦跨越边界
Once your F-18 strike team crosses the border
雷伊泰号航空母舰
Tomahawk missiles from the USS Leyte Gulf
就会同步发射战斧飞弹攻击这座机场
will launch a synchronized strike
on the enemy's airfield here.
炸毁那里的跑道
This will knock out their runway.
但你们还得对付已经升空的战机
But you'll have to contend with any planes already in the air.
战斧飞弹击中后，敌方就知道你们来了
The moment those Tomahawks hit
the enemy will know you're coming.
抵达目标时间是2分30秒
Your time to target will be two minutes and 30 seconds.
超过时间就会遭到
Any longer than that and you will be exposed
没被击中的战机攻击
to any aircraft the Tomahawks may have missed.
这是你们受训的目的
This is what you've all been training for.
安全回来
Come home safely.
让他们好看
You give 'em hell!
长官
Sir.
长官？
Sir?
我…
I...
我只想说…
I just want to say--
等安全回来…
We'll talk
我们再聊
when we get back.
嘿，布雷德利！布雷德利
Hey Bradley! Bradley!
嘿
Hey.
你行的
You got this.
独行侠
Maverick.
独行侠？
Maverick?
你在吧？
Hey you with me?
我不喜欢那副表情
I don't like that look Mav.
我只有这一号表情
It's the only one I got.
谢谢你
Thank you.
要是我不能再见到你，宏多…
If I don't see you again Hondo
谢谢你
thank you.
这是我的荣幸，上校
It's been an honor Captain.
匕首一号，准备弹射
Dagger One up and ready on Catapult One.
匕首候补，待命中
Dagger Spare standing by.
匕首四号，准备好了
Dagger Four up and ready.
匕首三号，准备好了
Dagger Three up and ready.
匕首二号，准备好了
Dagger Two up and ready.
支援军机起飞，攻击小队准备好了
Support assets airborne. Strike package ready.
等待起飞指令
Standing by for launch decision.
出发
Send them.
匕首二号，起飞
Dagger Two away.
匕首三号，起飞
Dagger Three away.
匕首四号，起飞
Dagger Four away.
侦察机，匕首一号报到
Comanche Dagger One. Standby check in.
侦察机就定位
Comanche 11 set.
空域安全，建议匕首小队继续任务
Picture clean. Recommend Dagger continue.
收到，匕首小队低空飞行
Copy. Daggers descending below radar.
匕首小队低于雷达，切换至鹰眼影像
Daggers now below radar. Switching to E-2 picture.
前方是敌方领地
Here we go. Enemy territory up ahead.
60秒后登陆，控制中心，回报状况
Feet dry in 60 seconds. Comanche Dagger One. Picture.
前方安全，你的决定
Comanche. Picture clean. Decision is yours.
收到
Copy.
展开攻击
Dagger attack.
战斧飞弹已经发射
Tomahawks airborne.
没有回头路了
No turning back now.
匕首小队，组成进攻队形
Daggers assume attack formation.
组队飞向目标
Daggers set. Proceeding to target.
2分30秒，三、二、一…计时开始
Two minutes and 30 seconds in three two one mark.
-二号计时开始
-三号计时开始
-Two mark.
-Three mark.
四号计时开始
Four mark.
进入峡谷
Going in.
飞过第一个炮台
First SAM site overhead.
我们没被雷达侦测到
Looks like we're clear on radar Mav.
别掉以轻心
Let's not take it for granted.
更多炮台，三点钟方向
More SAMs! Three o'clock high!
-两分钟后抵达目标
-收到
-We got two minutes to target.
-Copy.
我们落后几秒，公鸡，得快点
We're a few seconds behind Rooster. We got to move.
战斧飞弹30秒后击中跑道
Thirty seconds to Tomahawk impact on enemy airstrip.
匕首小队
Dagger Comanche.
我们侦测到两架敌机
We're picking up two bandits. Single group two contacts.
-它们从哪来的？
-长程巡逻？
-Where the hell'd they come from?
-Long-range patrol?
它们的航向是什么？
Comanche what's their heading?
航向090，目标西南50哩
Bull's-eye 090 50 tacked southwest.
它们没看到我们，飞走了
They're headed away from us. They don't know we're here.
战斧飞弹一击中空军基地
The second those Tomahawks hit the air base
敌机就会折返防卫目标
those bandits are gonna move to defend the target.
我们得抢先一步，加速
We have to get there before they do. Increase speed.
我们会跟上，别等我
We got you Mav. Don't wait for me.
匕首二号和四号进度落后
Sir Daggers Two and Four are behind schedule.
抵达目标时间，1分20秒
Time to target one minute 20.
战斧飞弹将于三、二…
Tomahawk impact in three two...
击中目标，机场跑道全毁
Impact. Enemy runway is destroyed.
他们知道我们来了
They know we're coming now.
敌机转向前去保护目标
Bandits are switching course to defend the target.
公鸡，你在哪里？
Rooster where are you?
快点，敌机来袭
Come on Rooster. Bandits inbound.
我们得赶上，快加速
We got to make up time now. Let's turn and burn.
小心，凤凰
Heads up Phoenix.
敌机距离目标两分钟，匕首小队一分钟
Sir bandits are two minutes from target.
Daggers are one minute from target.
快啊，公鸡，不快点就会死
Come on Rooster. Move it or lose it.
我们落后了，真的得加速
Guys we're falling behind. We really got to move.
现在不加速
If we don't increase our speed right now
敌机就会在目标那里等着我们
those bandits are gonna be waiting for us
when we reach the target.
爸，该怎么做？
Talk to me Dad.
加油，你行的，别犹豫
Come on kid you can do it.
放手去做
Don't think just do.
天啊，别那么快
Jesus Rooster not that fast!
这就对了，咱们上吧
That's it kid that's it. All right let's go.
该死，公鸡，慢一点
Damn Rooster take it easy.
匕首二号赶上来了
Sir Dagger Two is reengaging.
很好，击中目标就回来
All right now hit your target and come home.
30秒后抵达目标，巴布，检查雷射
Thirty seconds to target. Bob check your laser.
检查完毕，确认雷射辨识码1688
Air-to-ground check complete. Laser code verified 1688.
雷射待命中
Laser is a go!
小心
Watch your heads.
哇靠
Holy shit!
-复仇者，跟上了吗？
-在你后方
-Payback you with me?
-Right behind you.
凤凰，准备攻击
Phoenix stand by for pop-up strike.
匕首三号就位
Dagger Three in position.
倒数三、二、一，爬升
Popping in three two one.
-标示目标，巴布
-匕首三号
-Get me eyes on that target Bob.
-Dagger Three.
待命
Stand by Mav.
-快啊，巴布
-待命
-Come on Bob come on.
-Stand by.
-标示目标了
-锁定目标，投掷炸弹
-I've got it. Captured!
-Target acquired. Bombs away.
击中了，确认命中目标
We've got impact! Check direct hit! Direct hit!
那是第一个奇蹟
That's miracle number one.
匕首二号，回报
Dagger Two status.
就快到了，独行侠，就快到了
Almost there Mav. Almost there.
粉弟，雷射咧？
Fanboy where's my laser?
雷射出了状况
Rooster there's something wrong with this laser.
靠，雷射失灵…
Shit! Deadeye deadeye deadeye!
快点，没时间了，快点搞定
Come on guys we're running out of time. Get it online!
-我正在试
-快点，粉弟
-I'm trying!
-Come on Fanboy!
就快好了，快好了！
Nearly there! Nearly there!
-快啊
-来不及了，我要随意投掷
-Come on Fanboy get it online.
-There's no time. I'm dropping blind.
-公鸡，我行的
-来不及了，快走
-Rooster I got this!
-No time. Pull up.
-等等
-投掷炸弹！投掷炸弹
-Wait!
-Bombs away! Bombs away!
正中目标！
Bull's-eye bull's-eye bull's-eye!
第二个奇蹟
Miracle number two.
他们飞到棺材角
Now they're in Coffin Corner.
还没脱险
We're not out of this yet.
大家小心
Here it comes.
飞弹来袭，凤凰，向右急转
Radar warning! Smoke in the air. Phoenix break right.
匕首三号发射诱弹
Emergency jettison. Dagger Three defending.
又来一枚飞弹
Here comes another one!
匕首一号发射诱弹
Dagger One defending.
公鸡，回报
Rooster status.
天啊
Oh my God.
飞弹来袭
Smoke in the air!
-向右急转
-Break right Payback!
-Breaking right.
天啊，又来了
Oh my God here they come!
公鸡，飞弹在你正后方
SAM on your six Rooster!
发射反制火焰弹
Deploying countermeasures.
我没被击中
Negative contact.
匕首一号进行回避
Dagger One defending.
-回报状况，巴布
-凤凰、独行侠，向右急转
-Talk to me Bob.
-Break right Phoenix! Break right! Mav!
九点钟方向！九点钟方向
Nine o'clock! Nine o'clock!
公鸡，两枚在你正后方
Rooster two more on your six.
匕首二号发射诱弹
Dagger Two defending.
-复仇者，正前方
-发射诱弹
-Payback SAM on your nose.
-Dagger Four defending.
-七点钟方向
-回报状况，巴布
-Rooster tally seven o'clock!
-Talk to me Bob!
-正后方
-匕首二号发射诱弹
-On our six!
-Dagger Two defending.
-向右急转
-我看到了
-Phoenix break right!
-I see it!
我看到了
I see it, i see it.
匕首二号发射诱弹
Dagger Two defending.
靠，我没诱弹了
Shit I'm out of flares!
公鸡，回避
Rooster evade evade!
甩不掉它们！它们锁定我了 它们锁定我了
I can't shake 'em! They're on me! They're on me!
独行侠，不！
Mav! No!
匕首一号中弹，重复，匕首一号中弹
Dagger One is hit! I repeat Dagger One is hit!
独行侠被击落
Maverick is down.
匕首一号，回报
Dagger One status.
回报！
Status!
有谁看到他？
Anyone see him? Does anyone see him?
-匕首一号，回报
-没看到降落伞
-Dagger One come in!
-I didn't see a parachute.
我们得绕回去
We have to circle back.
敌机来袭，准备攻击
Comanche. Bandits inbound. Single group hot.
建议匕首小队往南飞
Recommend Dagger flow south.
一分钟后拦截
One minute to intercept.
快叫他们飞返航母
Get 'em back to the carrier now.
敌机来袭，匕首小队飞返基地
All Daggers flow to ECP. You have bandits headed for you.
独行侠呢？
What about Maverick?
跟他说他也无能为力，F-18打不过敌机
Tell him there's nothing he can do
for Maverick not in a goddamn F-18.
匕首后备要求进行空中支援
Dagger Spare request permission to launch and fly air cover.
不准
Negative Spare.
-展开搜救行动
-不行，空中有敌机
-Launch search and rescue.
-Negative. Not with bandits in the air.
-独行侠还活着
-今天不能再损失任何人
-But sir Maverick is still out there.
-We are not losing anyone else today.
命令他们回来
Get 'em home now.
匕首小队，不准救援
Dagger you are not to engage.
重复，不准救援
Repeat do not engage.
匕首二号飞返航母，确认
Dagger Two return to carrier. Acknowledge.
确认
Acknowledge.
公鸡，敌机逼近，不能回去
Rooster those bandits are closing. We can't go back.
公鸡，他死了
Rooster he's gone.
独行侠死了
Maverick's gone.
噢，不…
Oh no no.
匕首二号被击中
Dagger Two is hit.
匕首二号，回报
Dagger Two come in.
匕首二号，收到吗？
Dagger Two do you copy?
匕首二号，回报
Dagger Two come in.
你没事吧？
You all right?
我没事，你呢？
Yeah I'm good. You all right?
搞什么鬼？
What the hell?
-你来干嘛？
-我来干嘛？
-What are you doing here?
-What am I doing here?
我替你挡飞弹不是让你也落难
You think I took that missile
so you could be down here with me?
你早就该飞返航母了
You should be back on the carrier by now!
我救了你一命
I saved your life!
我救了你，那才是重点
I saved your life. That's the whole point.
你到底在想什么？
What the hell were you even thinking?
你叫我不要想
You told me not to think!
这样嘛…
Well
见到你真好
it's good to see you.
我也是
It's good to see you too.
有什么计划？
So what's the plan?
不是吧
You're not serious.
你在开玩笑吧
You've got to be shitting me.
F-14战机？
An F-14?
我开那玩意击落三架米格机
I shot down three MiGs in one of those.
那古董能不能飞都不知道
We don't even know if that bag of ass can fly.
-试试就知道
-独行侠
-Let's find out.
-Mav!
好吧
Okay.
-前面有人
-是啊
-There's guys up there Mav.
-Yeah.
-那里有更多人
-好吧
-There's more over there.
-Okay.
-开始跑吧
-好啊，跑，跑啊
-Let's start running.
-Yeah run. Run.
我会打信号要你充气
Once I give you the signal for air
打开这开关直到针头指到120
you're gonna flip this switch until the needle gets to 120.
引擎启动后
When the engine starts
马上拔除一切
you got to pull out the pins and disconnect everything.
-你了吗？
-我了
-You understand?
-Yeah.
好耶！
Yes!
我一上去就收起梯子
Once I'm up stow the ladder.
好吧，哇塞
Okay. Wow.
很久没开了
It's been a minute huh Mav?
天啊，这玩意超老旧的
Oh my God. This thing is so old.
好吧
All right.
-关闭座舱罩
-好
-Canopy?
-Clear.
两条跑道都被炸毁
Both runways are cratered.
该怎么让这老古董起飞？
How we gonna get this museum piece in the air?
你为什么延展机翼？
Why are the wings coming out Mav?
这是滑行道，不是跑道
Mav this is a taxiway not a runway.
而且是很短的滑行道
This is a very short taxiway Mav.
坐好了
Just hang on.
哇咧！
Holy shit!
快点，快点
Come on come on come on.
指针能运作
Needle's alive.
-独行侠？
-很好，快点…
-Mav?
-That's it. Come on come on!
好吧
All right.
-独行侠
-起飞罗
-Mav!
-Here we go.
天啊
Holy shit.
长官，收到公鸡的信号
Sir we're receiving a signal from Rooster's ESAT.
看起来是故障
But there seems to be a malfunction.
-信号又消失了？
-不是
-Have you lost him?
-No sir.
他进入超音速
He's supersonic.
他在飞行
He's airborne.
-用什么飞？
-长官
-In what?
-Sir.
侦察机回报一架F-14战机正在飞来
Overwatch reports an F-14 Tomcat is airborne
and on course for our position.
不可能，不可能
Can't be. It can't be!
是独行侠
Maverick.
公鸡，快联络航母
Okay Rooster get us in touch with the boat.
我正在试
I'm working on it.
无线电失效，没有雷达，一切都故障
Radio's out. No radar. Everything's dead back here.
-教我怎么做
-先是无线电
-What do I do? Talk me through it.
-Okay first the radio.
打开…
Throw the...
UHF-2断路器
the UHF-2 circuit breaker.
试试看
Try that.
有一大堆断路器，哪一个？
There's 300 breakers back here. Anything more specific?
不知道，那是你爸的领域
I don't know. That was your dad's department.
我会想办法
I'll figure it out.
两架敌机在底下五点钟方向
Mav tally two 5:00 low.
该怎么办？
What do we do?
听好，冷静点
Okay listen. Just be cool.
我们若是暴露了身分早就死了
If they knew who we were we'd be dead already.
他们来了
Well here they come.
-有什么打算？
-戴上面罩
-What's your plan?
-Just put your mask on.
记住，我们是同一国的
Remember we're on the same team.
挥手和微笑
Just wave and smile.
那什么信号？他在说什么？
What's that signal? What's he saying?
我不知道他在说什么
No idea. I have no idea what he's saying.
-这个咧？
-我也没看过
-What about that one? Any idea?
-No never seen that one either.
靠，他的僚机进入攻击位置
Oh shit. His wingman is moving into weapons envelope.
听好了
All right listen up.
我一下令你就抓住头上的圆环
When I tell you you grab those rings above your head.
那是弹跳把手
That's the ejection handle.
不能逃离他们吗？
Mav can we outrun these guys?
他们有飞弹和机关枪
Not their missiles and guns.
那就要空战罗
Then it's a dogfight.
一架F-14…对上第五代战机？
An F-14 against fifth-gen fighters?
关键不在飞机，而是飞行员
It's not the plane it's the pilot.
我不在你肯定会迎敌
You'd go after 'em if I wasn't here.
但你在啊
But you are here.
拜托，独行侠
Come on Mav.
别犹豫
Don't think.
放手去做
Just do.
看到飞弹就告诉我
Tell me when you see smoke in the air.
-飞弹来袭！飞弹来袭
-坐好了
-Smoke in the air! Smoke in the air!
-Hang on.
好耶，击落了一架！击落了一架
Yeah Mav! Splash one! Splash one!
又来一枚飞弹
Here comes another one.
公鸡，发射诱弹
Rooster flares! Now now now!
分配气阀
Splitting the throttles.
绕回去
Coming around.
-快锁定，快锁定
-锁定了
-Give me tone give me tone.
-You got him Mav! You got him!
发射飞弹
Taking the shot.
搞什么？
What the--
哇咧，那是怎样？
Holy shit! What the fuck was that?
坐好了，我要低飞
Hang on. We got to get low.
峡谷会干扰他的瞄准器
The terrain will confuse his targeting system.
他来了
Here he comes!
回报状况，他在哪里？
Talk to me Rooster. Where is he?
他紧追不舍
He's still on us!
-我们被击中，被击中
-可恶
-We took a hit! We took a hit!
-Damn it!
-快秀一些你的招术
-坐好了
-Come on Mav. Do some of that pilot shit.
-Brace yourself.
哇咧
Holy shit.
锁定他，发射飞弹
I got tone. Taking the shot.
可恶
Damn it!
没飞弹了，改用机关枪
Out of missiles. Switching to guns.
快啊，快啊
Come on Mav come on.
-击中了，独行侠
-还没结束
-You got him Mav!
-It's not over yet.
-最后的机会
-你行的
-One last chance.
-You can do this.
加油
Come on Maverick.
好耶，击落第二架
Yes! Splash two!
-我修好无线电
-好样的
-Mav I got the radio on.
-Outstanding.
-呼叫航母
-收到
-Get us in touch with the boat.
-Copy that.
天啊
Oh my God.
这家伙在哪里？
Where the hell is this guy?
他在正前方
He's on our nose.
弹药用完了
Damn it we're out of ammo.
飞弹来袭，公鸡，发射诱弹
Smoke in the air! Rooster flares!
好险啊
That was close.
没有诱弹了
We're out of flares Mav.
靠，他已经追上来了
Shit he's already on us.
情况不妙
This is not good.
-我们又被击中
-不不不
-We took another hit!
-No no no!
不能再被击中了
We can't take much more of this.
逃不了，只能弹跳
We can't outrun this guy. We got to eject.
-什么？
-必须爬升
-What?
-We need altitude.
我下令就拉下弹跳把手
Pull the ejection handles the second I tell you.
-等等
-没别的办法
-Mav wait!
-Rooster there's no other way.
弹跳…弹跳…
Eject eject eject!
快拉把手，弹跳
Rooster pull the handle! Eject!
把手拉不动
It's not working.
独行侠！
Mav!
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起，呆头鹅
I'm sorry Goose.
午安，两位，这是你们的救星
Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen.
This is your savior speaking.
请系好安全带
Please fasten your seat belts
收好桌子，竖直椅背
return your tray tables to their locked and upright positions
准备降落
and prepare for landing.
刽子手，你看起来不赖
Hey Hangman you look good.
我很厉害，公鸡，非常厉害
I am good Rooster. I'm very good.
航母上见
I'll see you back on deck.
我顺风飞行
Maverick is downwind.
没有起落架或尾钩 收起阻拦索，架起护网
No front landing gear. No tailhook.
Pull the cable and raise the barricade.
紧急迫降，架起护网！
Foul deck! Raise the barricade!
Go!
别告诉我引擎失效了
Please don't tell me we lost an engine.
-好，那我就不说
-好吧
-All right I won't tell you that.
-Okay.
还好吧？
You good?
我很好
Yeah. I'm good.
-你又击落一架敌机
-两架了
-Chalked yourself another kill.
-That makes two.
独行侠击落五架，他才是王牌
Mav has five. Makes him an ace.
米契尔上校…
Captain Mitchell! Captain Mitchell!
长官
Sir.
谢谢你救我一命
Thank you for saving my life.
我爸也会这么做
It's what my dad would've done.
嘿，独行侠
Hey Mav.
吉米
Jimmy.
潘妮在吗？
Is... Is Penny around?
她带艾蜜莉雅去航船
She took Amelia on a sailing trip.
有说几时回来吗？
Did she say when she'd be back?
她没说喔
You know she didn't.
你要喝什么吗？
Can I get you anything?
（谨献给东尼史考特）
字幕翻譯：黃文俊
雙語校對：秦仁